<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Julien Vermeersch&#39;s Portfolio Website</title>
    <link>/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Julien Vermeersch&#39;s Portfolio Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Does the Yield Curve Predict a Recession?</title>
      <link>/projects/project3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/project3/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Welcome to my blog on the relationship between yield curve inversion and recessions. In this section, I will discuss an analysis I did as part of my Data Analytics course at the London Business School.
Every so often, we hear warnings from commentators on the “inverted yield curve” and its predictive power with respect to recessions. An explainer what a inverted yield curve is can be found here. If you’d rather listen to something, here is a great podcast from NPR on yield curve indicators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GDP components over time</title>
      <link>/projects/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/project2/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my blog on the evolution of GDP and its components. In this section, I will discuss an analysis I did as part of my Data Analytics course at the London Business School.
GDP can be divided into 4 main components, which are consumption (C), business investment (I), government spending (G) and net exports (exports - imports). You can read more about GDP and the different approaches in calculating at the Wikipedia GDP page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An analysis of AirBnb prices in Hong Kong</title>
      <link>/projects/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/project1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Welcome to my blog on the prices of AirBnb in Hong Kong, China. In this section, I will discuss an analysis I did as part of my final assignment for the Data Analytics course I took at the London Business School.
 Exploratory Data Analysis(EDA) Looking at the raw values We use the glimpse function to get a brief overview of the data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
